Cambridge, Mass. First Church records, 1784-1968.
Congregational Library Archives
Cambridge, Mass. First Church records, 1784-1968.
RG4935
Congregational Library Archives
6.98 Cubic Feet
(8 boxes)
Cambridge, Massachusetts, was fist settled in 1630 and the first meeting house was erected in 1632. Public worship began in 1633 with Thomas Hooker and the First Church of Cambridge was formally established in 1636 with Thomas Shepard as the first minister. In 1650, 1706, and 1757 the second, third, and fourth meeting houses were constructed. The Parish split in 1829 between Unitarians and traditional Congregationalists after the parish severed its contract with Abiel Holmes over his refusal to invite Unitarian preachers into the church. In 1831 the newly formed Shepard Congregational Society built the fifth meeting house and in 1872 the sixth, and final meeting house was constructed. In 1919 the First Church and Shepard Congregational Society were incorporated into a single legal entity, the First Church in Cambridge. The First Church in Cambridge continues to serve the local community today. This collection contains the records kept by a number of ministers at the First Church in Cambridge as well as the records of various church organizations which were gathered by members of the First Church in Cambridge and include diaries, sermons, correspondence, meeting minutes, and financial records.
Adams, Nehemiah, 1806-1878
Albro, John A. (John Adams), 1799-1866
Appleton, Nathaniel, 1693-1784
Brattle, William, 1662-1717
First Church (Cambridge, Mass.)
Hilliard, Timothy, 1747-1790
Holmes, Abiel, 1763-1837
McKenzie, Alexander, 1830-1914
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were loaned to the Congregational Library & Archives by the First Church in Cambridge in 2010; accession 2010-01.
Custodial History
Prior to 2010 the records within this collection were deposited on loan to the Houghton Library at Harvard University.
Historical Note
Cambridge, Massachusetts, originally called Newe Towne and then Newtowne until 1638, was fist settled in 1630. The first meeting house was erected in 1632. Public worship began in 1633 with Thomas Hooker as the minister. In 1636 Hooker, and all but eleven members of his congregation, moved to Connecticut after he dissented from other Puritan leaders in Massachusetts. Thomas Shepard became the second minister in 1636 and the First Church was officially organized with him as the minister on February 1, 1636. It was the eleventh congregational church founded in Massachusetts. In 1637, Harvard was settled in Newtowne in part so that students could "benefit from proximity to the soul-ravishing preaching" of Rev. Shepard. In 1648 the Cambridge Platform of Church Doctrine and Discipline, an important document outlining church government in New England, was adopted in the First Church meeting house. Rev. Shepard continued to be the minister of the First Church until his death on August 25, 1649.
By 1650 the first meeting house had fallen into disrepair and the second meeting house was erected in the College Yard. Johnathan Mitchel succeeded Rev. Shepard in 1650 and served as the minister until his death in 1668. He was instrumental to the creation of the Half-Way Covenant which granted baptism to the children of nonmembers of the church. Rev. Mitchel was succeeded by Urian Oakes (1671-1682) and Nathaniel Gookin (1682-1692). In 1696, William Brattle, a 1662 graduate of Harvard, was installed as the minister of the First Church. During his time at the church he was also a tutor and treasurer at Harvard and a Fellow of the Royal Society of London. By 1703 the second meeting house had also fallen into disrepair and the town voted to begin construction on a third. Construction on the third meeting house was completed in 1706 and remained near the location of the second. Rev. Brattle's pastorate ended in 1716 with his death.
At 24 years of age, Nathaniel Appleton, was installed as the minister of the First Church in 1717. He is the single longest serving minister at First Church having served for 67 years until his death in 1784. Beyond his pastorate, Rev. Appleton was also a Fellow of Harvard and was the second ever recipient of the degree of Doctor of Divinity from Harvard in 1771. In 1718 the third meeting house was expanded. In 1753 the fourth meeting house was constructed. Timothy Hilliard was installed as an assistant pastor in 1783 while Rev. Appleton's health began to fade and in 1784 Hilliard was installed as the new minister. He served until his death in 1790.
Rev. Hilliard was succeeded by Abiel Holmes who was installed as the minister of the First Church in 1792. He graduated from Yale College in 1783 and became a minister in South Carolina and then in Midway, Georgia until 1791 when he permanently moved back to New England. In 1803 he was made a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and in 1805 he published his history, American Annals. In 1813 he was elected as a member of the American Antiquarian Society and served as the secretary there from 1816-1828. In 1829, Rev Holmes' contract with the Parish of the First Church was severed over his refusal to invite Unitarian preachers and his strict adherence to evangelical Congregationalism. As a result, a majority of the church's members withdrew from the parish and formed the Shepard Congregational Society, hiring Rev. Holmes to lead the new congregation. In 1831 the fifth meeting house was constructed by the Shepard Congregational Society at the corner of Mt. Auburn and Holyoke Street. Rev. Holmes continued to be the pastor of the Congregational Church until 1831 when declining health forced him to resign from the position. The parish which remained in the fourth meeting house eventually became the First Parish Unitarian and built their fifth, and current, meeting house in 1833.
In 1829 Nehemiah Adams Jr. was installed as an assistant pastor at the First Church. When Rev. Holmes resigned in 1831 Rev. Adams became the minister. In 1834 he resigned from the pastorate to become the pastor of the Essex Street Church in Boston. In 1835 Dr. John Albro was called to become the next minister of the First Church. Rev. Albro was both scholarly and community oriented, serving on the School Committee and often inviting students to his residence for the study of the Greek Testament. He published a work titled the Life of Thomas Shepard. He resigned in 1865 and died the following year.
Alexander McKenzie was installed as the pastor of the First Church in Cambridge in 1867. During his pastorate, the church's membership grew significantly. He founded the Young People's Alliance in 1882. He also maintained close relations with Harvard and other academic institutions; at Harvard he was the preacher to the University and the Secretary of the Board of Overseers and he was also a trustee of Wellesley College. In 1872, the sixth, and final, meeting house was constructed. That church was also known as the Shepard Memorial Church. The fifth meeting house was sold to the Roman Catholic congregation following the construction of the sixth meeting house. In 1924 that building was sold to Harvard. Alexander McKenzie served as the pastor of the First Church until 1910 when he resigned, though he maintained the title of pastor-emeritus until his death in 1914.
In 1919 the First Church and Shepard Congregational Society were incorporated into a single legal entity, the First Church in Cambridge. In 1957 the First Church joined the United Church of Christ. In 1991 the First Church adopted the open and affirming title. Renovations on the sixth meeting house were completed in 2000. The First Church in Cambridge continues to serve the local community today.
Ministers
Thomas Hooker 1633-1636
Thomas Shepard 1633-1649
Henry Dunster (interim) 1649-1650
Jonathan Mitchell 1650-1668
Charles Chauncey (interim) 1668-1671
Urian Oakes 1671-1682
Nathaniel Gookin 1682-1692
William Brattle 1696-1717
Nathaniel Appleton 1717-1783
Timothy Hilliard 1783-1790
Abiel Holmes 1792-1831
Nehemiah Adams 1831-1834
John A. Albro 1835-1867
Alexander McKenzie 1867-1912
Raymond Calkins 1912-1940
John H. Leamon 1940-1962
Wells Grogan 1962-1976
Allen Happe 1977-1999
Mary Luti 2000-2008
Daniel Smith 2008-present
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records kept by a number of ministers at the First Church in Cambridge as well as the records of various church organizations which were gathered by members of the First Church in Cambridge. The ministerial records within the collection contain extensive sermon records, and the diaries of Alexander McKenzie. The church organizations records within the collection contain meeting minutes, financial records, membership records, attendance records, and historical sketches.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into the two series listed below. Both series are further divided into subseries based on topic. Within each series, materials have generally been arranged in chronological order by start date. Materials have also been grouped together by subject matter when there is a clear continuation of content between volumes.
Series 1: Ministerial records, 1784-1914
Subseries 1: William Brattle records, undated
Subseries 2: Nathaniel Appleton records, undated
Subseries 3: Timothy Hilliard records, 1784-1788
Subseries 4: Abiel Holmes records, 1788-1837
Subseries 5: Nehemiah Adams records, 1826-1834
Subseries 6: Samuel Green records, 1830
Subseries 7: John Albro records, 1864-1865
Subseries 8: Alexander McKenzie records, 1846-1914
Series 2: Church organizations, 1813-1968
Subseries 1: American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions records, 1813, 1821
Subseries 2: Missionary Sewing Circle records, 1819-1870
Subseries 3: Female Tract Society records, 1819-1875
Subseries 4: Margaret Shepard Society records, 1830-1932
Subseries 5: Maternal Association records, 1833-1856
Subseries 6: Holmes Chapel Association records, 1857
Subseries 7: Freedmen's Aid Society records, 1864-1875
Subseries 8: Church Aid Society records, 1870-1875
Subseries 9: Ladies Union Missionary Society records, 1872-1891
Subseries 10: Young People's Alliance records, 1884-1929
Subseries 11: Sunday School records, 1888-1968
Subseries 12: Captains of Ten records, 1889-1932
Subseries 13: Woman's Foreign Missionary Society records, 1892-1923
Subseries 14: Knights of King Arthur records, 1897-1934
Subseries 15: Woman's Home Missionary Society records, 1900-1920
Subseries 16: Riverside Alliance records, 1900-1928
Subseries 17: Parish Auxiliary records, 1916-1923
Related Materials
The Houghton Library at Harvard University continues to hold onto some First Church in Cambridge materials, including an account book and sermon papers whose digital representation can be accessed as part of the Congregational Library & Archive's New England's Hidden Histories project.
Additional records books from the First Church in Cambridge, and related to the church, are held by the Massachusetts Historical Society.
Bibliography
Calkins, Raymond. First Church in Cambridge, Congregational. 1946. 17.11.1 C14.24 FirC
Church music -- Societies, etc.; Church records and registers.; Church youth groups.; Diaries -- Authorship -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.; Fraternal organizations -- Religious aspects.; Installation (clergy).; Ordination.; Sermons, American -- 18th century.; Sermons, American -- 19th century.; Sunday schools.; Women -- Societies and clubs.; Cambridge (Mass.) -- Church history.; First Church (Cambridge, Mass.)
- Ministerial records, 1784 1914; 1784-1914; 116 Files; (69 volumes, 47 folders)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the personal and sermon records of a number of pastors at the First Church in Cambridge. Of particular note are the sermon records of Abiel Holmes and the journals kept by Alexander McKenzie. This series also contains correspondence, meeting notes, scapbooks, and records relating to important memorial services.
  - William Brattle records, undated; 1 Folder
    This subseries contains the sermon records of William Brattle, the sixth minister of the First Church in Cambridge.
    - Sermons, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Nathaniel Appleton records, undated; 1 Folder
    This subseries contains the sermon records of Nathaniel Appleton, the seventh minister of the First Church in Cambridge.
    - Sermon fragments, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Timothy Hilliard records, 1784 1788; 1784-1788; 2 Folders
    This subseries contains the sermon records of Timothy Hilliard, the eighth minister of the First Church in Cambridge.
    - Funeral sermon for Nathaniel Appleton, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sermon, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abiel Holmes records, 1788 1837; 1788-1837; 24 Files; (2 volumes, 22 folders)
    This subseries contains the sermon and personal records of Abiel Holmes, the ninth minister of the First Church in Cambridge.
    - Sermons, 1788 1791; 1788-1791 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sermons, 1792 1808; 1792-1808 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sermons, 1811 1818; 1811-1818 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sermons, 1819 1829; 1819-1829 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sermons, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sermon fragments, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - New Years sermons, 1788 1804; 1788-1804 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - New Years sermons, 1805 1814; 1805-1814 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - New Years sermons, 1815 1826; 1815-1826 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Fast day sermons, 1792 1802; 1792-1802 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fast day sermons, 1803 1811; 1803-1811 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fast day sermons, 1812 1815; 1812-1815 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Fast day sermons, 1816 1824; 1816-1824 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Installation anniversary sermons, 1793 1805; 1793-1805 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Installation anniversary sermons, 1806 1812; 1806-1812 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Installation anniversary sermons, 1814 1822; 1814-1822 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Installation anniversary sermons, 1823 1829; 1823-1829 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Thanksgiving sermons, 1809 1820; 1809, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1816 1832; 1816-1832 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Subscription to print an Abiel Holmes sermon, 1820 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Weather diary and clippings scrapbook, 1830 1837; 1830-1837 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - Sermon catalogue, undated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Sermon indices, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Separated Materials
      These materials were removed from the Weather diary and clippings scrapbook, 1830-1837.
    - Extracts from the Cambridge Platform, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Nehemiah Adams records, 1826 1834; 1826-1834; 4 Folders
    This subseries contains the sermon and personal records of Nehemiah Adams, the tenth minister of the First Church in Cambridge.
    - Correspondence, 1826 1829; 1826-1829 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Sermons, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - Sermons, 1833 1834; 1833-1834 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Samuel Green records, 1830; 1 Folder
    This subseries contains the sermon records of Samuel Green.
    - Sermon, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - John Albro records, 1864 1865; 1864-1865; 2 Folders
    This subseries contains the sermon and personal records of John Albro, the eleventh minister of the First Church in Cambridge.
    - Sermon, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Alexander McKenzie records, 1846 1914; 1846-1914; 81 Files; (67 volumes, 14 folders)
    This subseries contains the sermon and personal records of Alexander McKenzie, the eleventh minister of the First Church in Cambridge. Of particular note are the near complete daily journals and the immense collection of sermon notes kept by McKenzie.
    - Journal, 1846 1850; 1846-1850 (Box 2, Volume 1)
    - Journal, 1851 1855; 1851-1855 (Box 2, Volume 2)
    - Journal, 1855 1860; 1855-1860 (Box 2, Volume 3)
    - Journal, 1861 1870; 1861-1870 (Box 2, Volume 4)
    - Journal, 1870 1885; 1870-1885 (Box 2, Volume 5)
    - Journal, 1885 1910; 1885-1910 (Box 2, Volume 6)
    - Journal, 1867 (Box 2, Volume 7-8)
    - Journal, 1883 (Box 2, Volume 9)
    - Journal, 1884 (Box 2, Volume 10)
    - Journal, 1887 (Box 2, Volume 11)
    - Journal, 1891 (Box 2, Volume 12)
    - Journal, 1892 (Box 2, Volume 13)
    - Journal, 1895 (Box 2, Volume 14)
    - Journal, 1897 (Box 2, Volume 15)
    - Journal, 1899 (Box 2, Volume 16)
    - Journal, 1900 (Box 3, Volume 1)
    - Journal, 1902 (Box 3, Volume 2)
    - Journal, 1904 1908; 1904-1908 (Box 3, Volume 3)
    - Journal, 1906 1907; 1906-1907 (Box 3, Volume 4)
    - Journal, 1910 (Box 3, Volume 5)
    - Journal, 1911 (Box 3, Volume 6)
    - Journal, 1913 (Box 3, Volume 7)
    - Journal, 1914 (Box 3, Volume 8)
    - Phillips Academy essays and orations, 1853 1855; 1853-1855 (Box 4, Volume 1)
    - Phillips Academy yearbook, 1855 (Box 4, Volume 2)
    - Phillips Academy yearbook supplementary materials, 1856 1889; 1856-1889 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      These loose materials were removed from the Phillips Academy yearbook, 1855.
    - Harvard essay book, 1859 (Box 4, Volume 3)
    - Evening meetings notes, 1860 1869; 1860-1869 (Box 4, Volume 4)
    - Sermon index and calendar, 1861 1866; 1861-1866 (Box 3, Volume 35)
      This volume contains a calendar and index of sermons preached by Alexander McKenzie that indicates the date, number, and subject of his sermons. The volume also contains some vital baptismal records.
    - Notes on St. John's Gospel, 1862 (Box 4, Volume 5)
    - Correspondence regarding call to pastorate of the First Church, 1865 1867; 1865-1867 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Acceptance of the First Church pastorate, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Notes on St. John's Gospel, 1868 1870; 1868-1870 (Box 4, Volume 6)
    - Sermon notebook, 74-91, 1869 1870; 1869-1870 (Box 3, Volume 9)
    - Sermon notebook, 93-109, 1870 1872; 1870-1872 (Box 3, Volume 10)
    - Sermon notebook, 112-118, 1872 1873; 1872-1873 (Box 3, Volume 11)
    - Sermon notebook, 181-206, 1878 1879; 1878-1879 (Box 3, Volume 12)
    - Sermon notebook, 207-231, 1879 (Box 3, Volume 13)
    - Sermon notebook, 232-251, 1879 1880; 1879-1880 (Box 3, Volume 14)
    - Sermon notebook, 252-270, 1880 (Box 3, Volume 15)
    - Sermon notebook, 271-291, 1880 1881; 1880-1881 (Box 3, Volume 16)
    - Sermon notebook, 292-311, 1881 1882; 1881-1882 (Box 3, Volume 17)
    - Sermon notebook, 312-336, 1882 1883; 1882-1883 (Box 3, Volume 18)
    - Sermon notebook, 337-361, 1883 1884; 1883-1884 (Box 3, Volume 19)
    - Sermon notebook, 362-382, 1884 1885; 1884-1885 (Box 3, Volume 20)
    - Sermon notebook, 384-404, 1885 (Box 3, Volume 21)
    - Sermon notebook, 405-425, 1885 1886; 1885-1886 (Box 3, Volume 22)
    - Sermon notebook, 426-448, 1886 1887; 1886-1887 (Box 3, Volume 23)
    - Sermon notebook, 449-469, 1887 1888; 1887-1888 (Box 3, Volume 24)
    - Sermon notebook, 470-494, 1888 (Box 3, Volume 25)
    - Sermon notebook, 495-516, 1888 1889; 1888-1889 (Box 3, Volume 26)
    - Sermon index, circa 1899 (Box 3, Volume 36)
    - Sermon notebook, 517-549, 1889 1890; 1889-1890 (Box 3, Volume 27)
    - Sermon notebook, 550-585, 1890 1891; 1890-1891 (Box 3, Volume 28)
    - Sermon notebook, 586-638, 1891 1893; 1891-1893 (Box 3, Volume 29)
    - Sermon notebook, 639-683, 1893 1894; 1893-1894 (Box 3, Volume 30)
    - Sermon notebook, 684-741, 1894 1896; 1894-1896 (Box 3, Volume 31)
    - Sermon notebook, 742-801, 1896 1898; 1896-1898 (Box 3, Volume 32)
    - Sermon notebook, 802-878, 1898 1900; 1898-1900 (Box 3, Volume 33)
    - Sermon notebook, 879-1202, 1901 1910; 1901-1910 (Box 3, Volume 34)
    - Poem, 1874 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      This poem was removed from the Bible verse notes, undated.
    - Notebook, 1874 1883; circa 1874-1883 (Box 4, Volume 7)
    - Letters to the First Church, 1881 1910; 1881, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1883 1914; 1883-1914 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Two hundred and fiftieth anniversary letter, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Supplementary manuscripts, 1889 1900; 1889-1900 (Box 4, Volume 8)
    - Twenty fifth anniversary correspondence, 1892 1893; 1892-1893 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Fortieth anniversary correspondence, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Fortieth anniversary correspondence, 1907 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Fortieth anniversary service, 1907 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Clippings scrapbook, 1907 1914; 1907-1914 (Box 4, Volume 9)
    - Autobiography manuscript, 1910 (Box 4, Volume 10)
    - Autobiography manuscript, 1914 (Box 4, Volume 11)
    - Memorial service, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Sermon index, undated (Box 3, Volume 37)
    - Glossary, undated (Box 3, Volume 38)
    - Bible verse notes, undated (Box 4, Volume 12)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 4, Volume 13)
    - In the Old Days manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Harvard Divinity School advertisement, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Church organizations, 1813 1934; 1813-1968; 84 Files; (59 volumes, 25 folders)
  This series contains the records kept by various church organizations and other auxiliary groups associated with the First Church in Cambridge. The records include meeting minutes, organization by-laws and constitutions, membership lists, correspondence, financial records, historical sketches, and pamphlets.
  - American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions records, 1813 1821; 1813, 1821; 1 Folder
    This subseries contains correspondence between members of the First Church in Cambridge and the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions.
    - Correspondence, 1813 1821; 1813, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Missionary Sewing Circle records, 1819 1870; 1819-1870; 6 Files; (5 volumes, 1 folder)
    This subseries contains the records of the Missionary Sewing Circle and includes meeting minutes, financial records, and membership records.
    - Records, 1819 1840; 1819-1840 (Box 5, Volume 4)
    - Records, 1840 1871; 1840-1871 (Box 5, Volume 5)
    - Membership records, 1833 1843; 1833-1843 (Box 5, Volume 6)
    - Account book, 1843 1866; 1843-1866 (Box 5, Volume 7)
    - Account book, 1853 1870; 1853-1870 (Box 5, Volume 8)
    - Keys, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Female Tract Society records, 1819 1875; 1819-1875; 3 Volumes
    This subseries contains the records and meeting minutes of the Female Tract Society and the Missionary and Tract Society.
    - Missionary and Tract Society records, 1819 1834; 1819-1834 (Box 5, Volume 1)
    - Society records, 1828 1854; 1828-1854 (Box 5, Volume 2)
    - Society records, 1855 1875; 1855-1875 (Box 5, Volume 3)
  - Margaret Shepard Society records, 1830 1932; 1830-1932; 15 Volumes
    This subseries contains the records of the various organizations that fell under the umbrella of the Shepard name including the Shepard Singing Society, Shepard Benevolent Society, Margaret Shepard Society, and Shepard Guild. Included within the records are meeting minutes, secretary records, membership records, and executive committee records.
    - Singing Society records, 1830 1832; 1830-1832 (Box 5, Volume 9)
    - Benevolent Society records, 1866 1897; 1866-1870, 1897 (Box 5, Volume 10)
    - Society secretary book, 1880 1881; 1880-1881 (Box 5, Volume 11)
    - Society records, 1883 1886; 1883-1886 (Box 5, Volume 12)
    - Society secretary's book, 1886 1889; 1886-1889 (Box 5, Volume 13)
    - Society records, 1886 1898; 1866-1898 (Box 5, Volume 14)
    - Society records, 1889 1896; 1889-1896 (Box 5, Volume 15)
    - Society records, 1898 1905; 1898-1905 (Box 5, Volume 16)
    - Society records, 1906 1909; 1906-1909 (Box 5, Volume 17)
    - Society records, 1910 1912; 1910-1912 (Box 5, Volume 18)
    - Guild records, 1892 1932; 1892-1897, 1932 (Box 5, Volume 19)
    - Guild directory, 1898 1918; 1898-1918 (Box 5, Volume 20)
    - Guild records, 1909 1923; 1909-1923 (Box 5, Volume 21)
    - Guild executive committee records, 1910 1917; 1910-1917 (Box 5, Volume 22)